It's the end of the world as we know it.
Greenland is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Ric Roman Waugh.
John Garrity, his estranged wife and their young son embark on a perilous journey
to find sanctuary as a planet-killing comet hurtles toward Earth.
Amid terrifying accounts of cities getting levelled, the
Garritys experience the best and worst in humanity.
As the countdown to the global apocalypse approaches zero, their incredible trek
culminates in a desperate and last-minute flight to a possible safe haven.
John Garrity, played by Gerard Butler.
Allison Garrity, played by Morena Baccarin.
Ralph Vento, played by David Denman.
Judy Vento, played by Hope Davis.
Nathan Garrity, played by Roger Dale Floyd.
Dale, played by Scott Glenn.
Greenland is a 2020 American apocalyptic survival disaster thriller film
directed by Ric Roman Waugh and written by Chris Sparling.
The film stars Gerard Butler (who also produced), Morena Baccarin, Roger Dale Floyd, Scott Glenn, David Denman, and Hope Davis, and follows a family who
must fight for survival as a planet-destroying comet races to Earth while the people around them get more and more desperate to survive.
Originally scheduled to be theatrically released in the United States,
Greenland was delayed several times due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The film was released domestically by STXfilms, through video on demand on December
18, 2020, and then to streaming on HBO Max and Amazon Prime Video.
It was also released theatrically in other territories,
beginning with Belgium on July 29, 2020.
The film received generally positive reviews.
The film grossed $52.3 million worldwide with a
production budget of $35 million.
A sequel, Greenland 2: Migration, was released on January 9, 2026.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
panic, kidnapping, looting, natural disaster.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.